in this video we're going to look at how
to enter in receivables cash receipts
and Dynamics GP and compare that to the
experience of entering those customer
payments in Dynamics 365 business
Central in my GP system I'll go to my
cash receipts entry window and enter in
a payment we received from one of our
customers I'll go ahead and select the
customer that sent us the payment as
well as the payment amount I can then
next select the apply button where I can
find the invoice or invoices the
customer is
paying once I found the invoice I can
select the check box and choose okay
once I have all my information entered I
can go ahead and post my cash receipt
now let's see how we can enter in cash
receipts in business
Central to create customer payments in
business Central we'll select the search
icon and enter in cash receipts journals
once the search results appear we can go
ahead and select it from the
list in the cash receipt Journal we can
record a payment for that same customer
Adam park resorts once I've selected the
customer I can navigate over to the
apply to document number column by
selecting the lookup here I can see all
the outstanding invoices the customer
currently has with
us I can go ahead and find the invoice
select it and then choose okay
you can see how the payment amount has
automatically defaulted in for us and I
can post my cash
receipt in addition to cash receipts
journals you can also use the customer
reg register payments window to record
customer payments again I'll se select
the search icon and this time type in
customer register payments and select it
from the search
results in this window we can see all
outstanding invoices for all of our
customers customers let's say however we
want to filter the list down to just see
the outstanding invoices for Adam Park
Resort I'll select Adam Park Resort and
choose to filter on this value now we
only see the invoices for Adam park
resorts again I can find that invoice
that the customer sent a payment for
select the check box and it'll again
automatically enter in the amount
received and the date received and then
I can go ahead and post the payment if
everything has been entered in correctly
if the customer was sending a payment
for more than one invoice I can select
multiple invoices in the window and then
back under posting select to post as a
lumpsum payment in this video we've seen
how business Central provides a simple
and easy way to record customer payments
allowing for a more streamlined cash
receipt process